iflscience.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy | IFLScience

**Content provider privacy notice**

  1. 1\. Important information and who we are
  2. 2\. The data we collect about you
  3. 3\. How is your personal data collected?
  4. 4\. How we use your personal data
  5. 5\. Disclosures of your personal data
  6. 6\. International transfers
  7. 7\. Data security
  8. 8\. Data retention
  9. 9\. Your legal rights
  10. 10\. Glossary

**INTRODUCTION**     
Welcome to the IFLScience’s content contributor privacy notice.

IFLScience respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you submit content to us, or agree to us processing your personal data as part of our content (together referred to as “content”) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

**1\. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE**

**PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE**     
This privacy notice aims to give you information on how IFLScience collects and processes your personal data in connection with content, including any data you may provide to us when submitting content or contribute to IFLScience content (e.g. take part in an interview).

We do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

**CONTROLLER**    
IFLScience is made up of different legal entities, details of which can be found below. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the IFLScience Group so when we mention ”IFLScience”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the IFLScience Group responsible for processing your data. We will let you know which entity will be the controller for your data when you submit content to us or agree to us processing your personal data as part of our content.

We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below.

**CONTACT DETAILS**     
Our full details are:  
Full name of legal entity: IFLSCIENCE LIMITED  
Name or title of DPO: Susie Jolley  
Email address: [sjolley@iflscience.com](mailto:sjolley@iflscience.com)  
Postal address: 6 Kean St., London UK WC2B4AS  
Telephone number: +44 (0) 20 739 79 0441

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ( _[www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)_ ). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES**     
We keep our privacy notice under regular review.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

  2. **2\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified.

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.
  * **Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Image** means your image (either in static form or moving images) in connection with content.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA**     
Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to publish your content). In this case, we may have to cancel the contract you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

  3. **3\. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity and Contact by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
  * submit content;
  * complete an image release form;
  * complete a contributor’s release form;
  * complete an actor’s release form;
  * enter into any other contract with us in connection with content.

  4. **4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * On the basis of your consent.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**     
We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please _Contact us_ if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Specified Purpose (as set out in any applicable form/ contract agreed to by you)

| 

·         Image

·         Identity Data

| 

·         Consent  
  
Managing our relationship with you, including:

·         Notifying you of changes to our privacy notice.

·         Storing your contact details so that we can contact you.

·         Keeping a record of your consent.

| 

·         Image

·         Identity Data

·         Contact Data

| 

·         Necessary for our legitimate interests (to maintain a record of your contact details in case we need to contact you regarding the content; to keep our records updated).

·         Necessary to comply with a legal obligation.  
  
**CHANGE OF PURPOSE**     
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please _Contact us_.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

  5. **5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

  * Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

  6. **6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

We may share your personal data within the IFLScience Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ).

We ensure your personal data is protected by requiring all our group companies to follow the same rules when processing your personal data. These rules are called “binding corporate rules”. For further details, see _[European Commission: Binding corporate rules](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/binding-corporate-rules_en)_.

Many of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see _[European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)_.
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see _[European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)_.
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see _[European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en)_.

Please _Contact us_ if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

  7. **7\. DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

  8. **8\. DATA RETENTION**

**HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?**   

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.

  9. **9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.

**NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED**     
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU**     
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND**     
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**     
You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to use the content. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please _Contact us_.

  10. **10\. GLOSSARY**

**LAWFUL BASIS**     
 **Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by _Contacting us_.

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

**THIRD PARTIES**     
 **IFLSCIENCE GROUP**

  * **UK - IFL SCIENCE LTD  
** Company Number: 9435049  
Registered Office:  
6 Kean Street  
London  
WC2B 4AS

  * **US - IFL Science LLC  
** Registered Office:  
2711 Centerville Road  
Suite 400  
Wilmington  
19808  
Delaware

  * **Canada - IFLS INC.  
** Ontario Corporation #: 002352096  
Registered Office:  
471 Aberdeen Blvd.  
Midland  
Ontario  
CANADA  
L4R 5L9

**INTERNAL THIRD PARTIES**     
Other companies in the IFLScience Group acting as processors and who are based in the US and provide IT and system administration services and undertake leadership reporting.

**EXTERNAL THIRD PARTIES**   

  * Professional advisers acting as processors including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the UK and the US who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
